<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Historical Income Panel for the Netherlands</title><link>https://hip-nl.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Historical Income Panel for the Netherlands</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 10:55:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hip-nl.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Presentations in 2023/2024</title><link>https://hip-nl.github.io/news/presentations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 10:55:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hip-nl.github.io/news/presentations/</guid><description>Some recent presentations by the HIP-NL project:
2024 EHS annual conference SSHA 2023 EHES 2023 A slidedeck presenting the state of the project and inequality trends in the Netherlands can be found here</description></item><item><title>HIP-NL at the 2023 Posthumus conference</title><link>https://hip-nl.github.io/news/posthumus2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hip-nl.github.io/news/posthumus2023/</guid><description>Eva will present about the HIP-NL project at the Posthumus Conference. We&amp;rsquo;re in the session on Fiscal sources for the study of inequality on Wednesday the 24th, 1500.</description></item><item><title>Team</title><link>https://hip-nl.github.io/team/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 01:15:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hip-nl.github.io/team/</guid><description> Auke Rijpma Paul Puschmann Eva van der Heijden Rick Schouten</description></item><item><title>The HIP-NL project</title><link>https://hip-nl.github.io/project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 23:55:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hip-nl.github.io/project/</guid><description>The Historical Income Panel for the Netherlands project (HIP-NL) is creating a unique large-scale historical income panel. Using municipal tax records income estimates at 10-year intervals will be gathered for c. 200,000 individuals in the Netherlands between 1851 and 1922. Recent mass digitisation of vital records and population registers, as well as the development of data integration tools means we will be able to connect the income panel to many other important economic and social history datasets, and answer questions about social and economic inequality over a long time frame, across multiple dimensions, and over multiple generations.</description></item></channel></rss>